for sure and Google another another one
of those those good home all of my
devices like in front of me just blit up
when I said
that stop stop I'm not I wish you had
didn't have headphones back okay Google
turn the lights on exactly
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone this is techno geek here
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
our latest sponsor project Discovery now
project Discovery makes a lot of tools
that you probably know of or have even
used uh one of them is nuclei and the
latest release of nuclei is version 3.2
now 3.2 comes with a lot of really
awesome new features um two that I
really wanted to highlight here for you
are the authenticated scanning and the
advanced fuzzing support now for
authenticated scanning it used to be
that you would have to do all your
nuclei scanning against unauthenticated
end points or you'd have to add your
cookies manually all that kind of messy
no more it's all automatic you can use
existing login templates to
automatically log in to your application
and then you can run all your existing
nuclei templates against an
authenticated part of the application
now to really increase your coverage uh
the other that I mentioned is Advanced
fuzzing support now nuclea had added way
back in version 2.8 the ability to fuzz
different things but now they've
expanded this comprehensively across the
board so not only can you fuzz in the
normal spots but you can fuzz within
headers you can fuzz within cookies you
can fuzz within specific parts of the
body whether that's in Jon or XML or
form data and so many more things so if
you want to learn more about what came
in nuclei 3.2 go ahead and check out the
the release blog post over at nu. g/p
podcast that's n ux. g/p podcast thanks
all righty guys I am feeling the podcast
energy today man we just got off like a
like a awesome brainstorming session on
how to make the critical thinkers
Discord tier super valuable and now we
got our boy Ben back on the Pod welcome
Ben second time hopefully it's better
than last time so n dude it it's that's
actually you should you're looking at
the podcast analytics and you just see
this big boom this big peek that goes
and I was like what is that what is what
did we do right there and it's like ah
we had been on the podcast I'm assuming
it's probably the YouTube algorithm
loving the the user and probably yeah
yeah makes sense that was a fun podcast
too though there's a lot of BL blindex
that said stuff and I know I'm looking
at the notes for this episode I feel
like we're going to talk more about
cross-site scripting anyway so here we
are nothing nothing wrong with a good
cross-site scripting man I you got to
love it you got to love it but but you
just um you just came back from bsides
right yeah bsides was really really fun
uh um this is our second year going to
bsid me and J hadex we host the bug
bount Village there and we went back
again we uh we did an event with Adobe
we did some like live hacking events not
live hacking event but like live Recon
more than anything with Adobe and then
um yeah did some workshops and went to
some talks and lots of hackers were in
town I don't know if you saw nagly Sam
and Ian were out there I saw the
pictures man met Facebook's meow's team
was there um lots of cool people to see
and hang out with dude I feel like B
sides is just not really on my radar as
much as it I mean obviously you you hear
about like Defcon and naham con and lots
of these other you know cons pretty
pretty uh often but for some reason I
always forget about uh bside San
Francisco so I I think that actually is
one of the more maybe it's just me
forgetting about it but I think that is
a stealth really really good conference
because I went I want to say in like 200
18 and they had some great great talks
yeah I think a lot of the bside stuff
depends on where you are right well B
San Francisco it's like right before RSA
happened so the I'm I'm not really like
I'm not big on RSA cuz it's not it's
Enterprise I don't have really a lot of
stick in that game right but it's cool
to go and everyone comes in for RSA they
go to bide San Francisco and then it's
like some of the more Community stuff
happens there but you also have these
like big sponsors that are out there too
the cool thing is a lot of these like
quote unquote I say quote unquote
content creators come out so you know
like you see people that are going to
RSA for that same specific reason and
you just run into them at the same time
uh it's a very exciting week it's not as
exciting as like Defcon the the summer
camp that we have every year but it
makes you like okay I'm almost ready for
death gone yeah yeah what what what kind
of so you said you went to some you did
the bug Bounty Workshop which I I want
to hear more about but you also went to
some cool talks including one by The
Meta team right and you said you were
pretty impressed with that program right
yeah actually so um Farah I've known
Farah for years and she was at B Crow
previously and then she just left and
went to meta I think and not recently
but you know she's been at meta for a
while now but uh I I just ran into her
you know it's like what are you up to
and uh one of our one of the bug Crow
folks I was there was like hey let's go
see this meta talk it's supposed to be
their bug Bounty program and it is
mindblowing to see what meta is doing
with their program dude like I think
their their top boundy right now is like
300K if you RC some of their big
production sites oh my gosh D imagine
popping a 300K bug that's a you know
that's 300K sometimes used to be what
hackam one paid at a at an event in the
early days of like the Live Events right
yeah and then like meta's over here like
hey we pay 300K for an RC and the other
cool thing is that I don't if you guys
know they have a loyalty program too do
you know about that oh oh like uh like
we're gonna have to bleep that but but
yeah like the bleed program talk about
exactly I was like I it came out of my
mouth and I was like oh wait I probably
shouldn't say that so uh yeah like the
bleep program that you just mentioned
but know they pay you like they they
tier you in like different tiers and
then depending on what tier you're on
you get a bonus so they were saying like
you could probably get you know another
20K bonuses depending on what tier you
are what kind of bugs you find things
like that yeah and they're doing the
promotion for a new bug Bounty Hunter
they gave me a coupon thing I've never
submitted to The Meta program but right
now if you submit to them you get up to
x% on top of your uh vulnerabilities
which is really cool dude that I don't
know Joel you you've done a little
hacking on meta right that's it's an
intimidating Target but the payouts are
freaking good not a little you just had
a sick xss didn't you yeah yeah I yeah
okay so yeah we did find an xss on
Facebook core uh with some caveats and
there is a space raccoon blog post about
that um however uh I will say it is a
really cool um you know group of
products and platforms to hack on um
it's very very dense I think a lot of
the people that hack on that are like
specialized sort of hackers like that is
what they focus on a lot of what they do
just hacking on meta products so they're
very familiar with the ecosystem and
everything and how it works and how
Stuff communicates with each other and
the common types of bugs and they have
their own gadgets and all sorts of stuff
so yeah um I think I think they've got a
cool iot um ecosystem as well right like
the portals and the glasses yeah those
and then um I think they also have a lot
of really loyal client side hackers
because they really care about atto I
think yeah the atto stuff is insane dude
um yeah one of the things that they were
saying with their vulnerabilities also
is if you tell them like hey I have this
vulnerability and I think I can do X Y
and Z with it they will give you an
authorization from these this time to
this time to try it out and if you can
actually prove it to them they'll like
do it and then on top of that they go
and um do their own in investigation so
if they find more systems that are
vulnerable to that vulnerability or that
technique they give you the max payout
for that bug this is just all that stuff
that Farah was talking about her during
her um Talk and it it's it's a very
interesting program do you imagine like
you're getting an ssrf on Facebook and
Facebook says cool go out and like show
us what you can actually do with this
right wow cool that that's cool that
they give you like a time frame where
they're like actively monitoring and
like you know sort of figuring out what
exactly you can do um yeah shout out to
um Jason Grace on their team uh he's
like on the propal team and he's like in
between some of the bug Bounty stuff he
was talking about I think it's the way
explained it was very very cool it's
like hey I was on a pentest myself and I
found a BL xss but I asked him to let me
explore it more and he said I went to BL
xss to xxc to
rce he's like that's like something that
you don't see most programs let you do
that we stop at BL xss like we get
critical payouts for it but I want to
pop a show on this admin panel if I can
like that' be really really cool right
oh my gosh yeah absolutely if you can
pivot on that that that'd be really
awesome get access to the admin panel
and then now you're you're attacking
stuff that was never meant to be
external that's pretty rad that they
that they let them do that I I really
dig that yeah I I know that there have
been a couple hackers recently
particularly hackers that are talented
in client side stuff yeah sort of
pivoting over to meta to try to try them
out as a as a long-term program because
it's not something you really I mean I
say it's not something you do sort of
for a short-term thing but we we've also
had some success I mean Joel had some
success doing it for an l and I've had
some success doing an L with them in the
past but um definitely think it's better
as a long-term like this is my Homebase
sort of program where they'll you you
know you learn the team they treat you
well you get good bounties you learn the
ecosystem I mean if you're spending
three months on like a program like that
and you get like a 50k Bounty that
that's a good return for three months of
work right absolutely I feel like with a
lot of like the regular bug bounding
programs you you have to do quantity to
make up because of the bounty amounts
aren't as high as you would expect them
to be but I think with a big program
like that I agree dude
yeah I I agree you so you mentioned
before you did the bug Bounty Workshop
man can you give me like can you give me
the tldr of that I wish i' had been able
to make it out there this year yeah well
unfortunately our we had Labs ready and
digital ocean had an incident I think
Adam caused an incident maybe but he
tweeted about saying I I saw about that
yeah I think two other Nam servers were
up and we just couldn't spin up new
things anymore so like last minute we
had to change it and I look at Jason I
go so what do we do he goes we do what
we do best Recon I'm like all right so
we're going back and forth talking about
like different friend methods of finding
domains and different things you can do
we actually talked about like some of
the CSP stuff that he talked with you
guys about uh at uh at uh bsides and
then we just did a little bit of Recon
and some tooling and things like that
and good turnaround and then uh and
again shout out to the adob team for
letting us uh use them as a target for
some of our Recon stuff sweet was the
Adobe team out there yeah they were out
there they were doing a lot of they
wanted uh I think they're including Fire
firefly on their bug Bonny program it's
they're like uh
from my remember it used to be like a
note taking thing I think now it does
more uh so they want to get that tested
it's like AI meets meetings and I think
it's supposed to have eventually I saw
in the comments like Twitter that
they're supposed to be like video
editing too very nice very nice that
sounds like a that sounds like a good
Workshop yeah there was a new Google
product that launched that sounds kind
of similar to that too there was Google
Google video I think they call it it's
it's like a new Google Docs Google Drive
type offering where it's interesting
cheats and and slides and stuff but it's
a video editor that's based in your
browser I wonder if it's like replay
where you can like live comment on
videos like you know for editing and
things like that or you they they showed
a lot of that kind of stuff where it's
you know it's very AI driven and like
you know collaboration driven so you can
be like you know let's put this in here
and in the same way that you can
collaborate in Google Docs and stuff but
sounds like an interesting uh hacking
Target it sounds like to me yeah for
sure and Google another another one of
those those good home all of my devices
like in front of me just blit up when I
said
that stop stop I'm not I wish you had
didn't have headphones be like okay
Google turn the lights on yeah
exactly don't don't don't steal that um
all right man
so we've it's been announced it's out
there your boys are hosting naham con we
are super excited for this and we've got
some announcements for this week right
yeah it's uh it's an exciting time so
people watching May 24 May 25 is the
conference we have May 23rd is what TF
kick hop 24th we have workshops uh and
then on the 25th we have all our main
talks and I just announced on Twitter
that sh is actually the keynote uh
speaker and he's going to do some like
wa bypasses originally it was like
smaller wa bypasses that he was going to
talk about I'm actually like looking at
his um cfp right now to see what it was
but he's doing large attack surfaces
more than anything else like he's like
if you have a large attch surface this
is what you do so some of the things to
talk about is like also using using some
custom templates he's going to talk
about like fuff on a single host then
some burp plugins and then he also has
some uh bypasses for smuggling that he's
gonna talk about too gez man that guy
has an endless source of content I swear
and if that was if that wasn't enough
there's also a workshop for two hours on
Friday on just wa bypasses with labs and
things like that so wow with him or with
no it's uh so yesb hack is one of our
sponsors and they wanted to do a talk on
it and it was like it's like an hour and
a half and I'm like dude I can't an hour
and a half talk let's do a workshop and
they're like yes so I I know I don't
know about you guys but I get like a
[__] ton of tweets that like hey where
is how do I do W bypasses how do I do
laugh things dude so many people and and
like I swear because once you get in
this industry it's like into content
Creation in this industry people will
message you and they'll be like hey you
know I've got this xss and I can't get
past this WAFF and I'm like okay you
know I can do this and then I always sit
down for like you know a couple minutes
and I'm like let me bypass this thing
then I just get tilted you know and I'm
like so annoy
there are some there are some you know
techniques that that can help with it so
I'm excited to learn a little bit more
about that I think there's a good Roi
for us in particular with that sort of
thing too because we can help all these
people dming us yeah I know you guys did
some stuff with um WordPress recently
it's different sponsor but we have a
different sponsor coming in doing a
workshop on WordPress hacking actually
and like finding VES on uh WordPress
plugins how do you do it and things like
that and also CTF around there too so I
know you guys' critical thinking uh
people that you have on your Discord
were really active on that so if they
want to come and do some ctfs you also
have that too very good man very good
yeah we just actually I want to say Joel
earlier today is when we moved the my my
WordPress automation script into the for
I just so I had some private automation
that I built when I was really into
WordPress um plug-in stuff uh in the
beginning of this year and essentially
it monitors for any plugins entering a
certain a threshold of of uses and it
also monitors for common code patterns
uh for vulnerabilities in various um
Ajax register functions um within the
WordPress code um those that plug-in
code and then it pushes to a a Discord
web hook um whenever that get gets in
place so essentially over the past
couple months I've just I'll just
randomly drop a like a WordPress plugin
zero day into the critical thinkers chat
and be like here you go guys just go and
report this yeah yeah cool that's
amazing dude yeah
um but that's not all with thecon right
like like I I'm just excited for this
last bit there's more you know we try to
keep we we try to keep the opportunities
pretty clean here on critical thinking
you know we we we try to keep the um the
things that we talk about pretty
relevant and add a lot of value to the
listeners and nothing adds value like
$50,000 am I right Financial value a
little bit of
value so so now we're just going to jump
into it yeah so the another sponsor was
like Yahoo and the paranoid specifically
and you know you guys have I think
probably one of your first bug bounties
was Yahoo it was man it was same my my
MB belt was from a Yahoo event oh the
New York event yeah yeah uh so yeah
they're a sponsor and you know with a
lot of our sponsors what we want to do
is like want to think of like how do
they get value and then we do this thing
with Noam for Community I can talk about
that later too but how do we make it
more fun for the community well also
this like sponsors also happy right so
they they I got a call with him they're
like hey we have 50,000 I go 15 they go
no no no five is zero in bonuses and I
go okay
like that's insane all right like we're
doing something big and like yeah like
obviously we can't give more and like we
know we want to like get people to get
active what can we do and I'm like okay
let's just like brainstorm so we
brainstorm a lot with him shout out to
the paranoid team they were very very
good to go back and forth yeah they're
doing some amazing stuff so yeah $50,000
in bounty
and there is a not bouncing bonuses and
there's pretty much a bonus for
everybody dude like anyone anyone that
wants to try out this program they can
get a bonus you dropped a a list here in
the chat let me see if I can pull it up
dude there's a critical thinker bonus
isn't there so there's one called the
critical thinker there is one for uh
there's multiple we don't want to
mention everything but if you have you
know if you find something that's CRI is
probably gonna get a bonus something
with high it's you know depending on the
numbers will I find it it might get a
bonus medium might may get a bonus but
there's also like cool stuff like like I
don't know how long it's been since you
guys have hacked on The Bu Bounty
program it's been a little while for me
so if you're returning you're returning
hacker you know you get you ignited with
the program you may get a bonus there is
a lot of cool stuff in there so don't uh
you know first of all like go find bugs
there's assets that are in SC are going
to get uh bonuses too so don't worry
about like hey am I going to qualify
there's so much in there that I feel
like everyone could qualify I feel like
up to 50 people maybe not 50 people but
there's a good 20 30 people that could
get bonuses I'm looking at these numbers
it's it it may be close to that man cuz
you got these 30 yeah 37 bonuses right
now oh my and it goes up to it goes up
to $10,000 for some and then uh you know
up to 500 for some of the other ones so
so here's a little double click into the
live hacking event life for you guys
really with with this because one of the
um let's just talk about like one of the
more advanced strategies when you uh
become like in the live hacking event
Serv or circuit is how do you optimize
these bonuses how do you hack on these
targets not only that are are going to
be getting you bounties and getting you
enough bounties but are also going to
land you these bonuses that companies
just kind of throw money at these
specific assets so um this is this is a
cool opportunity to kind of feel what it
feels like to have uh these bonuses
tacked on like we get at the live
hacking events all the time and funny
you say that that's literally when I sat
down I was like how do I come up with
bonuses you know like how do we do this
so it's like more fun for every like how
do we do that life iing events you know
how do we do it where you just ask and
you just pretty much think of like what
are what what are some of the cool
bonuses that we had at these events and
there it is so there there's going to be
more information on this coming out soon
I think by the time this podcast comes
out a lot of it's going to be announced
uh but yeah if you're watching this if
you're a critical thinker you're someone
on their Discord if you're on if you're
watching this not even on Discord at all
you know you can hack and it doesn't
have to be on one platform either it
could be on either platform out from
that the Yahoo program is hosted on to
it's pretty sick dude pretty sick
opportunity L stuff brought to the
public here very good dude um I I I
really I really do also like the uh the
reigner thing like the the people that
used to be engaged with the Yahoo
program and want to come back because
they hold a lot of knowledge right in
their heads and in their you know inbox
about the Yahoo program and you can kind
of bring that back in and reignite your
your engagement with that program is the
same thing with the hacking events are
you some of your top hackers because
they have you know value and then they
they get invited to the program for the
the events right that's kind of the same
idea um but juel do you want to give us
one more but wait there's
more but wait there's
more there's one more thing uh more
value I think and then also I I'm you
know I think with with education and
content creation I think going to Vegas
I had a friend of mine that I will keep
Anonymous but this person didn't want to
stay for Defcon one year at h172 and
it's like hey you should just stay we'll
get you a room just stay and hang out
and he he went to h172 he went to Defcon
and he was like oh my God this is so
cool like I wonder why I've never done
this like I met so many different people
that kind of like energize me and I'm
like super excited about it and I never
expected any of that I was just I want
this person to just stay and hang out
more and this year you know we thought
about like okay if this person calls me
tells me like hey that was really
valuable for me and they're already in
the industry they've done you know Vegas
every year because of their job or what
whatever it is what do we do for someone
that has never had the chance to go to
Defcon so as a part of the partnership
with Yahoo also one person is going to
get a full ride scholarship to go to
Defcon so which is uh your your flat and
hotel being paid for I don't think
there's going to be like food and stuff
like that unfortunately but the big lift
is on us you know we're going to book
you a flight we're going to book you a
room uh hopefully get you a badge and
you get to go and enjoy Defcon uh from
Thursday through Sunday and have a blast
and hopefully make some you know make
some friends do you think we can sneak
him into h172 as well that is a really
good idea I'm working on maybe also you
know getting that other half of the week
and like because I think it's a really
cool thing to go to h172 dude especially
if you're bug Bounty Hunter already
right 100% man that adds so much value I
think if me and you both pull out the
puppy dog eyes on on Caitlyn or Jessica
we might be able to make it happen so I
I know they I know they watch these
podcasts so Caitlyn Jessica Ari and uh
Harley you guys are watching this we are
going to beg you please let us make this
happen but honestly please but yeah I
haven't thought about it that far
there's a little bit of logistic ner
with being s to h172 because it's
somebody else's event the customer the
client and then also leave for the NDA
stuff and stuff like that so and then
the community parts of it also like
people are very entitled to some opinion
sometimes but we'll see uh to be
determined we'll know in like a week or
two maybe we'll announce that in the
hcon who knows very cool man well I am
super excited either way it's going to
be a blast and uh really looking forward
to all that whoever whoever lands the um
and and this scholarship this is for
people that performed well in the Yahoo
challenge right it's it's going to be at
random we're not going to say you know
it's not just performance space so you
don't have to be the top of the tier
hacker it's just we want someone that's
going to put in the effort so there is a
little bit of effort there so you have
to get some sort of a valid submission
and then at random we're going to pick
somebody that's going to want to go to
this event and then the first person
says no we go to the next one the next
one until someone says yes very solid
man it's going to be like the real LH
experience you got bonuses you got free
flights free hotels a bunch of community
we just don't have a belt I'll make my
own n Nom belt and just n belt just take
one of the belts and like just paste
your face over
it that's man yeah so that's all of it
so if people that want to get involved
even if you don't want to go to defcom
there's a lot of money for grabs please
like go and hack on Yahoo and make some
money and that's addition to what you
would get on bounties too it's crazy I
I'm I'm super excited for naham Khan
this year it's going to be it's going to
be a uh a record setting one man I think
in the history of naham kons um it's our
fifth year so we gotta go out with the
bang dude for our fifth year Gotta Go
Gotta Go Hard yeah um so let's go ahead
and shift the conversation let's go talk
about some some technical stuff um we
got some cool CSP stuff and we got some
cic CD stuff where do we want to go we
start with I think SD would be cool
because we can also talk about a little
bit of a launch on some stuff that you
guys have on your notes but yeah oh yeah
that'll be that'll be real fun I so all
right let me let me start with that then
just just to to give to give Lupin his
his due here so um our boy Lupin he came
on the Pod we did an episode with him in
uh in Japan uh and that was one of my
favorite episodes to record to be honest
because one he's got so much passion and
his accent sexy and the backdrop of that
episode was really good um so one go
check out that episode two
our boy is launching a product and it is
a freaking amazing thing that has uh
sort of stemmed from this whole cicd
research that man I guess this whole
dependency confusion thing stemmed from
a live hacking event where aj Chapman um
and and uh not not I'm sorry Alex bearon
um and I were working on there bearon
did have a have a A or Chapman did have
a part of that event but it was a
different thing um Al Alex beon and I
were sort of working on P related bugs
and this whole dependency confusion
thing came out um and then you know
Lupin sees this and he's like this is a
crazy industry a crazy scope surrounding
cicd stuff and he's built this tool
called deppy um that he's going to be
releasing and this is an an Enterprise
product to help secure the uh cicd chain
and I've seen this thing all right dude
hold on let me send let me send you this
link this link is not public yet um but
you got to go to this link and tell me
that I saw dude i i c on it yeah it's a
pretty pretty interesting design it's a
very cool design it's very unique and I
know he's worked really hard on this uh
cuz I you know him and I chat once in a
while he was one of the people that
reached out to me when I went to my
burnout I would just go back and forth a
lot it's like I'm so slammed with making
this happen and then when I saw the side
I'm like holy crap this is gorgeous yeah
dude it's it's an amazing product and
it's also just technically really
interesting because he's been kind of
keeping me in the loop while he's doing
the research that that powers this thing
and he's got so many like zero days
in all of these package management
softwares that he uses to get this sort
of dependency confusion um and uh and so
I'm really excited for that for that to
launch uh and I just wanted to give it a
shout out here because it's a product
that I really really believe in so if
you haven't haven't checked out cicd
stuff definitely check out um it's at
www.l and. teppy it will be live by the
time this podcast is live uh so we can
go ahead and Shout It Out yeah very cool
stuff I'm excited to see what he does
with it and yeah I'm sure he's going to
have a lot of like research come out of
it too with this being released yeah
we're going to we're going to have him
on for an episode in a couple weeks to
talk about the technical details of that
which I'm super hyped for but you've
also been doing some cicd stuff right
mine isn't so much like the dependency
confusion stuff mine is just mostly on
these couple of pentests that I've been
on um it's always like hey we we want
you to do a pentest but we're not going
to give you credentials to start with
it's like great love it like it's it's a
phase one right but like what do you do
like so much you can do with JavaScript
files and if it's like if they're using
some like framework like say like Jango
or something right then your chances are
going to be a lot less you know Jango is
just an example but whatever PHP
framework or whatever language they use
so you got to just really think about it
but I just it all started with just like
a dog ignore file with me there was like
four Assets in scope and it just started
with like a do get ignore file that
leaked a lot of like paths and I'm like
if they have this file on here like I
wonder what else is on here too right
like what else can I find on these other
apps that they own so huh so wait the do
ignore file you were looking at that for
things that they didn't want included in
the GitHub repo but might have been
accessible via a web server somewhere
yeah so if you look at get ignored it's
like for tracking like it's it tells you
like hey ignore these files they don't
track them right and sometimes like
they'll have like folders for like logs
they have like the upload folders in
there and it's just they don't want to
change it or they don't want to track it
um the upload ones like interesting if
you can find some stuff the logs ones is
interesting but then look at the bottom
there's also like configuration files
sometimes right this one specific
typically one of the the companies had
uh I don't remember what the path post
but they had like their gitlab CI files
in there like you can see all the
different depositors they work with and
you can you can look for dependen and
confusions in that way right but then it
gets worse when they have like a a
config.js file in there and it has like
credentials inside you sort of think
about like hey if there's like get
ignore is one of them you can't rely on
like a all. txt word uh wordless right
that you can't just throw everything at
it you need to be very specific of like
hey what is get ignore used for what is
get lab C yo file for and then finding
specific names that are similar to it
and that's like where AI becomes super
super handy
dude yeah no I I could totally see that
it that that that technique is not one
that I've actually super thought about
and I wonder if you could take if you
could find some way to correlate GitHub
repos to the what you're seeing on a web
server like you create a tool that
correlates that either through like the
dogit file being exposed or something
like that and then
create very high signal alerts where you
download the dot getting nor file you
pull the paths down hit the web server
on those paths and then if any of those
come back you assume that that's going
to be super interesting which I imagine
it yeah and the other thing is like if
they're using some you know one tool on
this asset what other tools are they
using on the other ones like if they
have a config out Json on this one like
what are some other like files that
could be a Json file that has credential
inside of it I think the the thing is
like we can't think of those names I
don't know if you guys are like that but
I can't think of those things when I
have this like Rush of like oh my God I
found this what else can I do Tunnel
Vision on the same file name um so
that's when like something like AI
giving good I reso has a really good uh
command that hits uh GPT and then it
pulls like a list of files based on what
you give it so you give it like six
files name file names like yam files dot
files and config files and you go hey
give me 50 more and then some of those
hit on some of the other web assets that
the get. get ignore wasn't accessible
right I don't see a lot of those anymore
but the ones that you see that dog bug
Bing programs don't see them because
everyone's running templates now and
doing boot forcing and things like that
but once in a while you still see them
pop up it's interesting to dig
into yeah yeah I bet with the with the I
guess popularity increase of nuclei
you're you're you're not seeing as many
of these like dot dogit files being
exposed and stuff like that in in any
meaning yeah I'm curious to see how
people write a nuclear template for a
dog get IGN nor file because there is
nothing that's like identified in the
headers they can say this is a do get
ignore file there is no like unless you
find a word. yl in there maybe but
that's like very I don't know I think it
could be a false positive it's hard to
fingerprint hard to fingerprint ah yeah
that's true I also think that whatever
you do with with um you know Mass Recon
I think the it's a whole another sector
it's a whole another distribution to do
that one layer deeper right so like
let's say for example you're scanning
for dogit everywhere right um there's
hundreds of people doing that but there
aren't hundreds of people hitting gal
hitting way back running a a quick hits
Brute Force list taking that first layer
of paths and then running all those
nuclei templates on under those paths as
well and I think I think that's there's
a lot of value especially with like apis
and stuff like that too right people hit
like SL actuator on API so they don't
think about doing API or like API app
names API and going down every folder
and you see a lot of more a lot more of
those than you see on like the web
rout absolutely yeah just as we continue
to talk about Recon stuff every time
you're oh do we lose them come back
sorry this camera has weird stuff
sometimes that's fine um as we continue
to talk about Recon stuff I uh I I
always sort of dream about building some
scanner that can
effectively check for path
traversal problems essentially where
where you can and I'm sure stuff out out
there exists I just haven't really
figured it out yet but I I remember
finding an RC one time on www right and
I just all all it was was and on a
pretty well-known site tooe like this is
a household brand that that's paying you
know I think it was like 6K crits at the
time and it's go to ww do do do do do
semicolon and then you get access to
this backend piece and you can just ACH
do semic colum slash no it just went
straight from there and so I I I keep on
thinking like there has to be a good way
to fingerprint where these traversals
are happening like you should be able to
do just a normal dot do slash and then
compare it to a dot dot SL 2f or a do
you can do the size right the response
size you can compare and if it comes
back as like a 500 or something that you
ignore it but if it's like a 200 there's
probably something there if it's
normalizing correctly like you take
something that of course it's going to
normalize correctly and then you know
try to do these permutations and if they
aren't the same then you can say okay
well these actually should be the same
response so something sketchy is
happening here I don't know it's Pro
it's probably really hard to get to be
high signal but I feel like I feel like
there should be some way to do it I yeah
I think it's going to be difficult to
know what's garbage and what's not in a
lot of these cases like what is actually
a result that you want versus like an
error page or a random page that you
don't really care
about yeah yeah for sure all right man
um last last little topic we had this is
going to be a quick little pod today
because we we spent so much time
brainstorming about about content
creation stuff and and critical thinkers
to your stuff um but I did want to hit
on CSP related yeah so you mentioned in
here you you've got some CSP bypasses
for uh for Google Maps um and some other
Google products actually so why don't
you talk a little bit about that CU um I
love these I that these things exist
these are such good little gadgets to
have so yeah I think Google itself is
just a gold mine for bypasses like one
of the number one things I look for is
YouTube and Google when it comes to CSP
bypasses YouTube is I think my favorite
one actually last time I was here I
talked about finding an xss at a liveing
event and that company had a really hard
CSP bypass and YouTube was the one that
works so with YouTube actually for
people that are watching maybe we can
talk about what you know how CSP Works
um it pretty much allows you to call
scripts objects images files from
trusted sources uh they say is to
prevent multiple vulnerability types but
I I say that's BS it's probably for xss
mostly uh yeah more than likely for
modern applications there there I don't
know I feel like you can do and and this
last episode that we discussed with um
with Yohan I mean he just gave such a a
beautiful um Deep dive into uh CSP
related stuff and and there are a lot of
things you can do with it like the form
action related thing can can prevent you
from doing um when you don't have
specific when you don't have accss but
you can create these forms and sort of
do a A curf or a C- surf token leak um
that can definitely be helpful but uh
and then obviously of course you've got
anything that that's relating to like um
uh cross- site leaks can also be limited
by by CSP but certainly the primary
function of it is to prevent cross-site
scripting which is really tricky to do
when all these sites keep on like having
all these Gadgets in place that allow us
to pop stuff yeah so I think the YouTube
one is one I think uh you had one listed
for
um go Maps yeah so so Maps this one I
have to give credit where credit was due
I meant to mention this on on the Pod
with Johan and maybe we sort of uh
shouted it out but I want to say that
that was actually a tweet coming from
him Joel do you know if that's if that's
right I don't remember yeah I I want to
say he tweeted out a couple weeks ago uh
a
a uh Google like maps. googleapis.com um
bypass a CSP byass that is done via Json
P right um because one of the most one
of the most common ways to bypass CSP is
to find an endpoint where they're
utilizing Json P um and then actually
insert a full function call into the
Callback um and so we we we I showed
this one to Ben on on the pre-recording
Ben's like oh yeah I got like a couple
of these and he pulls out one for WW w.
youtube.com www.googleapis.com
www.google.com there's also another one
for accounts I can't find it but it's
like if you hit the oath on google.com
there like a callback function you can
do the same thing I'm going to find that
eventually because I just used it
recently but there's also that I think
it also goes beyond that too like this
is only when the companies allow you to
do Google they allow you to do YouTube
or they allow to do like whatever waft
they use or you know whatever companies
that they're they're trusting right but
there's also like the Json P thing is
also on their end if they have an OAS
floor you can hit or if they have like
some random uh JP that you can find it's
a it's a really interesting it's very
creative and one of the first things I
like to do is like always just do a site
on Google Dorking sit site.com and then
looking for callbacks for example and
you don't get them a lot of times but
there's been a few times you can find
them and it's really really really
useful and and these are pretty widely I
I feel like when you see a CSP they're
often like all right startu google.com
or start googleapis.com or something
like that so having these Json callbacks
on these really trusted domains is super
clutch so we'll we'll um we'll put these
in the description of the episode we'll
drop them in the in the hacker notes as
well we'll probably tweet them out um so
you should see them in in many places if
you follow critical thinking in any way
but um thanks for sharing these man
because these are definitely high value
gadgets to have in the in your back
pocket yeah for sure abely absolutely
and we're going to be for the critical
thinkers soon soon we're going to be
putting together some sort of potential
reference or collection of these gadgets
for these types of things so that uh you
know as you're hacking as you're going
through and you're sitting there and
you're one step away from an awesome bug
and you're like dang if only I had a CSP
bypass for blank well now you you have a
reference that you come check and you
can come see if somebody's already got
one that they've shared with as a stay
tuned for that because we're going to be
working on as a critical thinker myself
I'm looking forward to it guys
so's like oh wait pulling it up pulling
up right now like hey uh is this still
there that's great is this yeah that
that's great man that's that's really
good and I guess I just wanted to shout
out this this isn't in the dock so we're
going off off the thing there but um
there was a really cool piece of
research that I just can't get out of my
head um which was essentially a scenario
where you can't do this or with like the
full CSP byp pass right where you can't
do like a full function call in the call
back but you can do um you do have
something that that triggers JavaScript
so you're able to trigger some it just
doesn't allow you to do a function call
and um and so what this guy did with
this research that I saw was he would
include a script right like script dot
uh you know whatever and he would do
like as his as his callback he would do
opener dot child element. child element.
child element. child. child element
right so these are all just dots and
asky characters which are all allowed in
the call back even secure callbacks and
then obviously it's doing some sort of
function call at the end or else it
wouldn't be a jsonp callback so he ends
it with DOT click and then in JavaScript
you can pass in any parameters to a
function even if it doesn't take it and
it'll just kind of like shove them away
um so then what he would do was he could
click arbitrary buttons on a page that
was uh the opener of that page so you
you do a window. openen you redirect
your original page to like an ooth flow
and then you include that CSP which will
do go down on the parent page and click
the approve button for an oo flow or
something like that and approve your
ooth application and I'm like this is
such a genius technique to be able to
weaponize just one single function call
to ex on aent page how do you even like
think of that
I don't know man but when I read that I
literally sat there with my jaw open for
a while because I'm like wow um now you
don't even really need a a full CSP
bypass in order to get some impact
because sometimes you see these jsonp
end points and you can't you know
introduce a function call or anything um
so I I'll see if I can track down that
research and I'll put it in the show
notes um for for this one because I I
think I cannot give that I've mentioned
it on the Pod before but I cannot give
that research enough shout outs how
creative is I would love to didn't
understand how they do it once there's
been a couple of times when I have been
stuck with like these callbacks when you
can do a function uh there's a couple
other things too like when you can do
parentheses sometimes for some reason
but you can do like the tack the
backwards T is also one but it's just
makes it back yeah it makes it a lot
harder to exploit though but that's only
if you're desper for an alert of some
sort is to demonstrate it
right seriously and and I think actually
the cool thing about the research that
he me mentioned as well was I think by
default every WordPress site has that
Gadget built in that that you can't do
the you can't do the full function call
on the call back but you can do this
thing that he's describing so um it's
super easy to find a uh like a a a
WordPress site on any of these victims
right like most of them have them have
them set to like SL blog or something
like this and then it revers proxies to
a uh to a WordPress site so lots of uh
really awesome gadgets there as
well awesome all right man Joel I know
you got a hard stop right now um Ben
anything else you want to shout out no
shout out to you guys for bringing me on
this podcast and then also hosting the
hcon and hopefully uh the expectation is
me met with all the the hype that we're
building around the hcon this year oh
dude it's gonna be it's gonna be
freaking great I'm sure their schedule
is live so they can go and check out
check it out and then just reminder May
24th May 25th as the main conference
awesome and that's where where can they
where can they check it out the hon.com
go homc con.com there's a schedule on
there you'll see everything that's
happening just on their
website sweet awesome that's a wrap on
this pod I think peace everybody to you
guys and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ct. show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to Master
Class
amas hacks exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you there